SAMUEL VALDES GUTIERREZ

 \checkmark (+56) 963094096 (Mobile - Provisionary) \diamond \bigcirc (+44) 7732 596921 (Whatsapp) \diamond London, UK

✓ valdesgutierrez@gmail.com ♦ ♦ bigsamu.com ♦ ♠ Github ♦ 🖬 LinkedIn ♦ 🖪 Hackerrank

Engineer with 6+ years of experience in Finance and Hardware solutions, concluding a career shift into Software Development. Avid learner and self-disciplined with solid communication skills. Looking for entry-level positions in high-performant Software Engineering teams, preferably working with Full-Stack technologies. Strong knowledge of ReactJS and FastAPI frameworks, with a preference for Javascript and Python languages (but not exclusive).

EDUCATION

MSc Computer Science, Imperial College London

London, UK | 2020 - 2022

- Graduated with an overall Merit degree (70.91%) achieving Distinction in thesis dissertation.
- Undertook student representative role for 100+ student fellows during 1st academic year.

Online Bootcamp - Full-Stack Development, Coding Dojo

Seattle, USA | March, 2020 - Dec, 2020

- Undertook 10-month online course learning Full-Stack technologies.
- Main contents reviewed: HTML, CSS, Javascript, JQuery, AJAX, Python, Django, Java, Spring Boot, ReactJS, ExpressJS, NodeJS, SQL, MySQL, MongoDB, Git.

BSc Engineering, Pontificia Universidad Catolica de Chile

Santiago, Chile | 2006 - 2013

- Major in Mechanical Engineering, Minor in Automation and Control Systems.
- Graduated with an overall grade of 6.0 (out of 7.0), being within the top 6% of the class (1st Class Honorous).
- Tutored and supervised 100+ students as TA in courses such as Engineering Challenges and Accounting.

EXPERIENCE

Teaching Assistant, Coding Dojo

Seattle, USA | Aug, 2021 - Present

- Tutored 100+ online students, successfully impacting them in their career conversion projects into full-stack development.
- Contents tutored: same ones as taught in degree (refer to education section)

FP&A Controller, Credicorp Capital

Santiago, Chile | Oct, 2017 - Feb, 2020

- Established a new procedure for better allocation of the firm's expenses leading to savings of CLP\$ 100MM+.
- Streamlined P&L's reporting routines of each company's BU, reducing processing times from 1 week to 1 day.
- Developed in-depth expense analysis, giving valuable insight to the firm's directors for cost-reduction decision-making.

Sales Specialist, Hewlett Packard Enterprise

Santiago, Chile | May, 2016 - Sept, 2017

- Designed and implemented up to US\$ 50M data centre infrastructure solutions (server, storage & networking).
- Strategically drove loyalty for HPE products/services among corporate partners and customers to increase demand.

Network Architect, IBM

Santiago, Chile | Jul, 2014 - Feb, 2016

- Designed up to US\$20M pre-sales solutions for enterprise networking, VoIP, and wireless infrastructure.
- Certified in Cisco CCNA Routing and Switching (2015)

SKILLS

 $|\ HTML\ |\ CSS\ |\ JavaScript\ |\ NodeJS\ |\ Python\ |\ Java\ |\ C++\ |\ Ruby\ |\ Solidity\ |\ SQL\ |\ JQuery\ |\ AJAX\ |\ ReactJS\ |\ React\ Router\ |\ Redux\ |\ NextJS\ |\ Django\ |\ Flask\ |\ FastAPI\ |\ ExpressJS\ |\ NodeJS\ |\ Spring\ Boot\ |\ Truffle\ |\ Ruby\ Sinatra\ |\ Bootstrap\ |\ MaterialUI\ |\ Lodash\ |\ Axios\ |\ SQLAlchemy\ |\ Alembic\ |\ Pydantic\ |\ VSCode\ |\ IntelliJ\ |\ STS\ |\ Git\ |\ Postman\ |\ Swagger\ |\ JWTs\ |\ Macaroons\ |\ OAuth2.0\ |\ Wireshark\ |\ Spanish\ -\ Native,\ English\ -\ Fluent$

PROJECTS

- SeisEnt Platform. Designed and implemented Proof-of-Concept (Full-Stack application) presenting a solution for seismic data entitlement problem in the Oil and Gas industry (MSc CS degree dissertation, 2022).
- Teaching ML, Kaggle Style. Developed frontend of educational WebApp clarifying ML overfitting concept to students from Imperial College Business School. Code available here. (MSc CS degree group project, 2021)
- **DicomNav.** Built iOS app with a novel way of visualizing MRI images on an iPad device using the internal sensors of the device (*BSc Eng. degree dissertation*, 2012).